# ZAIN UL ABIDEEN

Rawalpindi, Pakistan · +92-3400603481 · xainulabideen600@gmail.com

Experienced Unity Game Developer with a passion for creating immersive and engaging gaming experiences. Skilled in Unity3D, C#, and game design principles, with a deep understanding of the Unity game engine. Collaborative team player with strong problem-solving skills and attention to detail

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Game District Nov,2023– Present

## **Software Engineer**

Some main responsibilities are:

- From prototype to complete product ongoing multiple phases of Product Life Cycle
- Communicating with production and marketing team in creating balance between Gameplay and KPIs
- Delivering highly scaled Products while maintaining Product Quality
- Working on complex mechanics and AI Behaviors
- Deep profiling for optimizing memory usage and stable framerates
- Working with advertisement packages and analytics tools for keeping track of player progression
- Utilizing Firebase for A/B Testing

SnackGamer Aug,2022– Oct,2023

# **Game Developer**

Majority of the role required:

- Writing player controllers from scratch
- Integrated third Party API & plugins
- Working on a complete game including the Designing aspect
- Writing complex AI Behaviors for Npcs in the game
- Developed and play tested 40+ game prototypes

Metal Games May,2022–Aug, 2022

### **Game Developer**

Worked with Voodoo Publications on Contract Basis

- Developed and iterated on new and interesting Game Ideas.
- Learned about collaborative work and better understood the design aspect of games
- Explored other genres like io, puzzle, simulation

**M.A.S Games** Oct,2021–May, 2022

### **Associate Game Developer**

M.A.S Games is a remote based company working with Giant Publishers like Rollics Games.

- Developing different Prototypes each week consisting of Unique Ideas
- Working as Team with others
- Getting to know about Good Marketing techniques

# **Mindstorm Studios**

July, 2021-Aug, 2021

## **Game Developer Intern**

- Learnt new tools and their implementation
- Developed skill essential for progressing in this Industry
- Mainly focused on the development, marketing and publications of Hyper Casual Games
- Also Participated in a Rookie Game Jam 2021 and got Third Place in it

#### **EDUCATION**

International Islamic University, Islamabad

September, 2019-Present

## **Bachelor of Science, Computer Science**

• Awardee of Full Fee Waiver Scholarship

## **SKILLS & OTHER**

Skills: Game Development and Design, C# Programming, Design Patterns with Proper Use Cases, Game Mechanics with Visual Polishing and Proper Feedback.

## **Portfolio & Links**

- <u>LinkedIn</u>
- <u>Itch.IO</u>
- <u>GitHub</u>
- Passenger Express BMX Bike Game